BASIC VERSION of Angular
Typescript is Object Orientated Lang.
1 Angular Js
2 Angular 2
Need Of TypesScript
Bcz Angular 2 Onwords Developed in TypesScript
History
Developed By Mircosoft 2012
It was designed by Anders Hejlsberg (designer of C#) at Microsoft
its coding style is used like C++
The ECMAScript specification is a standardized specification of a scripting language
ECMAScript standard + ECMAScript version6 + Additional features=Typescript
Advantages
1 Strong static typing
       -TypeScript is a typed language, where we can specify the type of the variables, function parameters and object properties
inferred Type to mention Data type of Variable if not mentioned its by deafault take "any"
2 Find Compile Time Error 
3 Supports 
  - Classess
 - Inheritance
 - interface
- enum
- Function Overloading
- Function Override
Disadvantage
- Browser Don't understand Typescript
Installation
Steps
1 Installed Node
2 npm install -g typescript
 -npm= Node Package Manager
- g = globally
Identifier
- Both Character & Digit are allowed
- 1st letter should be character
- 1st letter of digit is not allowed
- special character are not allowed Except (_ and $ )
- No spaces are allowed
- No any keywords are used for identifire
e.g. 
var a;
var a1;
var a_b;
var a$b;
Above all are allowed

Below are not allowed
var 1a;
var 1_a;
var a b;
Variable: var, let, const
Data types
 - number,string,boolean,any,void
null - Represents an intentional absence of an object value.
undefined - Denotes value given to all uninitialized variables

Null and undefined ─ Are they the same?
The null and the undefined datatypes are often a source of confusion. The null and undefined cannot be used to reference the data type of a variable. They can only be assigned as values to a variable.

Type Assertion
1 angle bracket <>
2 as syntax













//